If you are an NRI then there is great news for you
because health insurance
companies are providing special discounts to NRIs today.
Because
if you are an NRI, then if you want to
take a claim in future, then it is necessary for you to come to India.  That
means, whenever you visit India
, there is an emergency, a
medical emergency or suppose in future
you are going to
shift your embassy to India, then in such cases
you can take the claim in India only.
Right?  So there is a special discount for NRIs
because the chances of the claim company coming to you here are
very less.  Since you will be
staying less here in India, the
chances of getting a claim are also very less.  So that's why
you get special discount.
Friends, if we talk about the
special discount available for NRIs,
I will tell you about three such plans in which you can get a
very good discount.
If we talk about the first plan, it is nba resor 3.0.
Next, if we talk about HDFC Ago's Optima
Secure and the next plan,
it is ICIC LBR's 11 plan. If we talk about the
discount for NRIs, how much discount can you get
in Re 3 point of NVM Health Insurance Company.
If we talk about discount in this planning,
you get 15% discount.  Just
think, earlier GST was 18%, that means 18%,
so your tax has been reduced.  Plus you will
get 15% more discount here.  Yes.
Next, if we talk about HDFC Ago Optima
Secure, here you are going to get
40% discount.  That means you will
get 40% discount.  But there are some
terms and conditions here.  If you have
taken the claim in the year in which your
discount amount is for that year, then basically you will
not get that discount.  You will have to return it.  For example,
suppose
your premium is Rs 50,000.
If we talk about a premium of Rs 50,000, if
we talk about 40% of a premium of Rs 5,000, then 40% is Rs
20,000, which means you got Rs 20,000 back in the first year.
What did you say next year too
?  Then you got 40% discount.
You got back Rs 20,000.
What did you do in third year?  You took the claim in the third year.
You will
not get that 20,000 discount.  You will have to return that 20,000.
Right?  Next company, if we talk about
ICICI LBD's Elite Plan, in the Elite Plan,
you have NRI Advantage
rider here, as soon as you tick it,
you will get 25%
discount here.  That means you can get 25% discount here every year.
But here the
maximum tenure of discount will be
5 years.  That means you can avail discount for 5 years.
After that you will
not get any discount in this plan.  Right friends,
here you will have to submit some of your KYC documents.  For example, if
you live overseas, then
you have to submit your address proof from abroad.
After that, you have to submit all your financial
documents etc.
Along with this, whatever Indian
documents you have, basically your
PAN, your Aadhar card if made
or your passport, visa where
your entry on exit visa is affixed, all these
documents will be
asked from you which are necessary for you to give so
that you can know that you are the NRI,
you are eligible for the special discount in
the case of NRI, so friends, first of all if
we talk about HDFC Air Optimus Secure,
here in this plan talk about USB, the
first USB is
Secure Benefit, that is, if you have
chosen a sum of Rs. 50 lakh, for example,
if you have taken a sum of Rs. 50 lakh, then
your sum of Rs. 50 lakh with Secure Benefit becomes Rs. 1 crore from day one.
Next if we talk about Plus Benefit,
what happens through Plus Benefit is
that your Sam Assorted will increase by 50% every year.
That means if you take a sum of Rs 50 lakh,
next year your sum will become Rs 75 lakh.
Then next year you will have a
sum of Rs 1 crore.  Another benefit is
pre-existing diseases i.e. A B C D
asthma, BP, cholesterol and diabetes.
You can get cover from 31 days with
extra premium or you
can get cover by taking writer.  Next friends, if we
talk about the next plan,
it is ICICI LB's 11 plan.  What is included in the 11 plans
?  If we talk about USB, the first
benefit that we talk about is
power booster.  Right?  What
happens through Power Booster is that basically
your sum will increase by 100% every year
and this will continue for
life as long as you keep the policy in force.
Suppose
you took a policy of Rs 50 lakh, then of Rs 1 crore,
then of Rs 15 crore, then every year
your sum will keep increasing by 100%, that is,
whatever your sum, the same sum will keep increasing
every year. Right next,
if we talk about Jump Start,
if you take a rider, then here it will be
basically your hypertension, diabetes,
obesity, asthma and hyperlipidemia, which
you can cover for 31 days with
extra premium.  The next rider
is Infinity Care.  If you
take Infinity Care Rider, then
you can make Infinity Care claim once in the entire policy term.
What is the USP of Re 3.0
?  Let us see.  The first
USP that the company introduced for the first time
in the health insurance industry is the
option of unlimited sum insured.  Meaning there is no concept of sum insured here.
You will get
unlimited sum insured.  Even if your first claim is of Rs
1 crore, Rs 10 crore
, Rs 20 crore or Rs 50 crore
, the company
is ready to pay your claim whenever it comes.  Right?  So here the
option of unlimited sum aso is available
in Resource 3.0.  Next, if we talk about it, there are
145 pre-existing diseases which you can
cover from day one.  If we
talk about this, there is another benefit in this plan and
that is Lock the Clock.  Lock the
clock means that the premium changes according to your age band,
for example, if you are 35 years old.  Now what will happen in 36
?  Your premium will increase.  But here
your premium will not increase due to age band.  There is an
option here which
is an inbuilt option or you do not need to take a rider.
That is Lock the Clock.  With Love the
Clock, your premium will never increase according to your age band.
But if you take the claim
then the premium will increase.
Another reason is that
if the company increases the premium due to inflation, then your
premium will increase.  But this
is the only benefit.  If your premium increases according to the age band, then the
premium will not
increase here.  Because of Lock the Clock.  Friends,
if you have to choose any plan, if you have to
purchase a health insurance policy
, then you should
look at the claim settlement ratio of the health insurance companies.  So
if we talk about claim settlement ratio,
HDFC Algo's claim settlement ratio is
99%.  The claim settlement ratio of ICICI LBA
is 97% and that of NIV is
92%.
If we talk about the denial claim ratio, that is,
how much premium the company collected and how much
claim they gave against it, then
if we talk about the
in-card claim ratio of HDFC Airgo, it is
81%, if we talk about the denial claim ratio of ICICI LBD, it is
79% and if we
talk about the denial claim ratio of NIV, it
is 59%, so here if we talk about the claim settlement
ratio and in-card claim ratio,
HDFC Airgo is looking the best.
Right?  Now let's talk about the solvency
ratio.  So the meaning of solvency ratio is
how much
liability the company has.  How many
assets do they have against them?  Right?  So if we
talk about the solvency ratio, that
of HDFC Aero is 1.68.  If we
talk about the solvency ratio of ICICI LBD, it is 2.68.
If we talk about NIIB, it is 2.55, that is, against the
liabilities,
they have that much assets.
Right friends, now let's talk about
network hospitals.  When
you purchase any medical from the company,
you should see that there should be maximum number of cashless hospitals in the network around you.
You must have
heard the news like KR Health Insurance and
Bajaj, their
tie up with hospitals is going to be cancelled.  Cashless will not be available completely.
As far as the recent news is concerned, it is going to be
settled and it has already been settled.
So here
if we talk about network hospitals, friends,
if we talk about network hospitals of HDFC Airgo, then 14,000
plus network hospitals are available with them.
If we talk about ICICI LBAT,
they have 15,000 plus hospitals for
cashless treatment on all
India level basis.  If we talk about
Nibapa, they have 11,000 plus hospital
cashless services.  After that
friends, if we talk about
any reimbursement process like pre and post, it
goes into reimbursement.  Plus, if there is ever a
cashless denial, you can
claim reimbursement.  So the
reimbursement claim process is basically the same as
in today's date, what used to happen earlier in many companies was that
you had to make physical deposits.
But what happens today is that the
submission is done online
in the companies' app.  So, in the plans of all three companies,
you can submit your reimbursement to all three companies on online basis.  The
companies provide your claim within a week or 10 days.
Right?  Next friends, if we talk
about Sama Assured Right, then how much Sama
can you take as Sama? If we talk about HDFC Aego,
in Optimum Secure you can take a sum of Rs. 5 lakh, 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh,
50 lakh and up to Rs. 1 crore. You
can take a sum of Rs. 1 crore in HDFC Aego Optimus Secure
Plan. Next friends, if we talk about
ICIC LBA 11 plan, you can take a sum of Rs. 5 lakh, 7 lakh, 10 lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh, 50
lakh, 1 crore, 3 crore
and according to you.
Next friends, if we talk about Nibhau
Resord 3.0, you get
unlimited sum asor here.  Friends, now let's talk about
policy tenure.  At what age
can you purchase the policy?  So here if we
talk about HDFC Air Optimum Security, we can
purchase policy for 1 year, 2 years and 3 years.
Here, if we talk about the
Eleven plan of ICICI LBT, you can purchase the plan for 1 year, 2 years, 3
years, 4 years and 5 years.
Next, here you can talk about Nibo Up
Restore 3.0, you can purchase policy for 1 year, 2 years, 3
years, 4 years and 5 years also.
Friends, now let's talk about
pre and post hospitalization, that is, the
expenses incurred before admission in the hospital and after discharge
basically go into reimbursement.
So here you get pre and post
hospitalization for 60
and 180 days, in HDFC Air, Optimal
Secure, you get 90 and 180 days in ICICI LB plan.
Here, if we talk about
VS and 3.0, you get 60 and 180 days
pre and post hospitalization.
Next, if we talk about day care
treatment, day care means that
you do not need to stay in the hospital for 24 hours.   For example,
if any technology is good today then
stone operations etc. are done.
So basically you do not need to be admitted for 24 hours.
If you are admitted for 10 hours or
even 12 hours basically, then that
admission is called day care.  So all three
plans have old day care cover.  All
daycare will be covered and up to the entire daycare
is covered in all three plans.  Next, if we
talk about modern treatment, friends.
Modern treatment
plays a huge role in your policy.  Right?  Like today,
many surgeries are robotic
surgeries.  And in the coming times, doctors are
also preferring robotic surgery for
modern treatment.  So here in all the
three plans, there is
no capping of modern treatment in any way.  So this
is a very big plus point.  If you
take any of the three plans, there is
no capping on modern treatment.
Next friends, if we talk about ambulance, then
up to the standard ambulance is covered in Optimus Secure.
Talking about road ambulance,
up to 50 road ambulances are covered in ICICI LB's Elevate plan.
So
up to the same road ambulance is covered in all three plans.
Next friends, if we talk about air
ambulance, then in air ambulance,
in Optimus Secure,
you get air ambulance for hospitalization above Rs 5 lakh.
Next, if we talk about IC
Lobert's Elevate plan, here up to
the front air ambulance is covered.  If
we talk about Reshore 3.0, here
your capping for air ambulance is ₹5 lakh.
Right?  Next friends, if we talk about
annual health checkup.  Annual Health Checkup
Basically if we talk about Optimus Secure
you get annual health checkup of ₹500
per lakh, the maximum
annual health checkup you get is of ₹
15000, next if we talk about Currency
lmb's 11 plan here also
you get health checkup of up to ₹5000, which is
listed according to your health checkup.
Next,
if we talk about Reed 3.0, you can avail the
option of health checkup through a rider.
Next friends, if we talk about
alternative treatment which is called
Ayush treatment like Ayurvedic, Unani,
Homeopathy and Siddha treatment.  So here's
Optimus Secure talk up to the
Samus cover.  Alternative treatments are covered in up to 11 plans
in all three plans.
Next let's talk friends about
maternity covered.  So,
if you take Optimus Secure plan for maternity cover, then
you
can cover maternity through Parenthood Rider.  Next, if
we talk about ICICI LBAT's Elevate plan,
in which 10% of basic sum
is available after 2 years.  There is some capping here also.
Next, if we talk about Reshoot 3.0,
you don't get maternity cover.  So
friends, this was the comparison of all three plans
after GST. Basically,
you will not be charged GST in all these three plans.
So, due to no GST being levied,
your premium has become much cheaper.  So now
in the coming slide we will see
how much premium you have to pay in which plan.
If we have taken the calculation of one age.
Ok?  Based on that calculation, we
will tell you how much premium you have to pay.
So friends, if we talk about the calculation of premium,
we have taken the premium calculation of a 40 year old male right along with
his wife and two children, that is,
we have calculated the premium of daily answer
accordingly, so if we talk about
how much premium will HDFC Bank Optima Secure pay for a
sum of Rs. 50 lakh, that is, if we consider Rs. 50 lakh,
what happens in Optima Secure from day one,
what will be your sum with secure benefit, that sum gets doubled for you, that is, a sum of Rs.
1 crore is formed
from day one, so
if we talk about basic coverage of Rs. 50 lakh, the premium will be
Rs. 4588, that is, the
premium of HDFC Bank Optimus
Secure will be Rs. 50 lakh, next if
we talk about Elevate plan of ICIC LBD,
which is a 40 year old male, talk about 2 + 2 and Rs. 50 lakh, the
premium is coming to Rs. 44348,
next if we talk about NIV
Right, we took the calculation of REES and 3.0, 40
years and 2 plus means he has a wife and two
children, 2 + 2, if we
talk about the premium, if we talk about the premium of Delhi NCR premium zone,
we have covered Safeguard Plus, plus
we have also added health checkup in it,
in this a rider has to be added,
even after adding the rider there
is an option of unlimited sums, the premium of the black variant which we have taken is
coming to 42486, that
is, in 42486 you get unlimited
coverage, right, along with that consumables are also covered
and health checkup is also covered, right
friends, if you have any plan related
inquiry or you want to purchase a plan
but you are not able to take a decision,
our IRD authorized insurance advisor will
help you.  By comparing the best plan
according to you, according to your city, according to
your age, we
can design the best plan for you.  So if you want you
can WhatsApp us.  If you want to
work with an agency.
You want to make a career in health insurance.   Even if
you are already an agent but are
unable to work for health insurance,
you can still contact us.  We
also recruit health insurance agents
across pan India.  Okay guys, that's all for
this video.
You must take advantage of GST.
If you have not taken health insurance then you must take it.
Thank you so much.  See you in the next video.
Bye till then.  Jai Hind Vande
Mataram.